Dharmesh Raut

Mobile: +91 98211 39721

Email: dharmeshraut@gmail.com

Seasoned Pricing and Revenue management professional. Rich 13 years of experience in Airline Pricing and Revenue Management. Experienced in conceptualising and successfully implementing revenue generation / maximisation strategies.

Acumen in data analytics. Developed multiple path breaking analytics for team and senior management for better understanding of trends, accurate forecasting and new opportunities within different customer segments.

High performing leader. Currently managing a team of 65 highly skilled analyst and managers which will achieve budgets of \$ 1.8 Billion for FY 18-19 (+7% YOY).

EXPERIENCE

Jet Airways India Limited, Mumbai, India May 2006 – Present

Jet Airways is the largest Airline of India with revenues of US\$3.1 Billion. It operates a fleet of 112 Aircrafts across 23 countries, including 43 cities in India. It employs over 16000 people globally. Jet Airways is part of Etihad Airways Partner Network with Etihad Airlines having 24% equity in the company.

General Manager Pricing & Revenue Management

- May 2017 Present International Network (FY19 Revenues: \$1.8 Bn)
- November 2015 April 2017 Domestic Network (FY19 Revenues: 1.4Bn)

Responsible for the overall Passenger and Passenger related revenue streams. Directly responsible for PnLs. Leader for a team of 65 skilled analyst and managers.

- Responsible for international markets with turnover of more than \$1.8 bn annualised
- Optimising overall pricing framework for International network including various segments like corporates, Online travel agencies and retail agencies etc.
- Driving online sales to reduce distribution cost.
- Work on marketing activates to boost sales.
- Drive the Revenue management team towards multiple inventory management strategies to maximise revenues.

Key Achievements

- 1. Successful Joint Venture with AFKL. Successful implementation of joint venture with AFKL in record time. Appreciated by AFKL and Jet 's top management for speed and accuracy. Turnaround of Paris and Amsterdam hub within 6 months of JV implementation. Negative margin to breakeven PnL using RASK improvement techniques (RASK +13.2% over three years).
- 2. **Growing Revenues and Profitability**. Achieved growth in revenue from USD 1.7 Bn to USD 1.9 Bn through aggressive pricing / inventory decisions. (RASK +7% YOY, where market fares are negative 10% to 18%)
- 3. **16% plus RASK YOY performance on Premiere Cabin**. With correct price positioning of Jet Airways Premiere product coupled with aggressive promotions and commercial strategy, 16.8% Premiere cabin YOY RASK improvement achieved.
- 4. **Successful turnaround of ASEAN flights.** Identified correct mix of traffic segments on ASEAN network. YOY RASK improvement of 5%, first positive YOY RASK performance in last 4 years.
- 5. **Introduced incentive plans for the team.** Jointly Implemented Incentive plan for Pricing and Revenue Management for first time in Jet airways (H2 FY 17-18). Achieved 100% success rate.
- 6. Mentoring multiple analyst to create future leaders.

Route Manager July 2009 – October 2015

Worked on all sub markets of jet airways including London, ASEAN, GULF, Domestic as route manager. Implemented key inventory management strategies to generate maximum revenue. **Key Achievements**

- 1. Successful implementation of Partnership with Etihad Airways. Achieved synergies between two inventory management departments. Successful implementation resulted in revenue improvement of Abu Dhabi gateway flight by 29%(RASK +7.8% YOY)
- 2. **Turnaround of GULF flight.** Successful turnaround of GULF market from loss margin of 25% to Profit margin of 25% using targeted inventory and pricing strategies, regular commercial reviews with sales teams.

Flight Analyst May 2006 – June 2009

Key Responsibilities

- 1. Handling key north India flights.
- 2. Handling long haul London flight.
- 3. Implemented key reports to improve overall efficiency and effectiveness of flight analyst processes.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Shop Floor Incharge April 2001 – April 2004 GKW Limited SnF Division, Mumbai, India.

Key Responsibilities

- 1. Ensuring smooth daily functioning of Shop floor.
- 2. Production planning and control for entire division.
- 3. Special Project management.
- 4. Key member of quality assurance team.

EDUCATION

Master of Management Studies (MMS) - Marketing, **IES College of Management Studies** 2004 - 2006

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engg) , **Mumbai University** 1998-2001